A Guide to the Papers of Creed Taylor
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Creed Taylor 1791-1873
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
1232, 1398
This collection consists of 416 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The library acquired this collection through gift and purchase in 1941 and 1942.
Biographical/Historical Information
Chancellor Creed Taylor of "Needham," was a lawyer and judge of the Superior Court of Chancery for the Richmond, Virginia. His estate, Needham, is located in southern Cumberland County, Virginia near the Farmville town limits. It was the site of the first proprietary law school (1821-ca.1830) in the state of Virginia, the state's second law school and the fourth in the U. S.
Scope and Content
The collection contains information on plantation life at Taylor's "Needham" and Judith Randolph's "Bizarre;" legal and financial matters; Virginia politics and the Republican Party; the law school maintained at "Needham" by Taylor; the Virginia Literary Fund to support public education; the division of Fincastle County, Va., in 1799; James Monroe's presidential bid of 1808; and cases before the Superior Court of Chancery, including one involving William W. Hening
Other topics include the Virginia-Kentucky boundary dispute of 1803; the necessity of a Republican university education (Eldred Simkins); a Virginia state bank (John Taylor of Caroline); a book endorsement; the Mutual Assurance Society (Alexander McRae); changes in the Virginia judicial system (Archibald Stuart, ); judicial procedure (Dabney Carr); residency requirements for judges of courts of chancery (Robert Nelson, William Nelson); safety of court records in war time (Archibald Thweatte); Mordecai's school in Warrenton (Samuel Taylor); the sale of Thomas Mann Randolph's estate and Randolph's distrust of Francis Walker Gilmer's motives; Taylor's incipient problem with alcohol (Samuel Taylor, 1828 February 27).
Also of interest are letters concerning the binding out of a free black youth (John Michaux, Nat Dodson) and the disposition of Taylor's property and the fate of his slave Rhody and her family (Samuel Taylor 1826 August. 28).
In a note, 1802 February 1, James Monroe sends a publication. In a letter fragment, ca. 1808, Monroe suggests corrections in the wording of an endorsement of his presidential bid by Taylor. In a letter, 1811 Janaury 21, he writes re the appointment of a Mr. Robinson to an unnamed position. In a letter, 1813 January 4, Taylor writes to Monroe recommending the appointment of William Randolph as Captain.
In a letter, 1813 January 4, James Madison writes re the appointment of R. M. Chapman as clerk of the Chancery Court at Fredericksburg.
There are several letters from admirers concerning Creed's Journal of the Law School including one from Thomas Jefferson,1823 March 24.
In addition the collection contains accounts of Creed Taylor as executor of Beverley Randolph.
The collection also contains the diaries, 1852-1856, of Jennette Knickerbocker, a Madison County, New York school teacher, as well as her correspondence with Albert Howard, Jr. The 1852 diary describes her year at an institute in Cazenovia, N.Y. (Cazenovia College?).
Contents List
- Indenture: James Fretwell and others, 1791 April 1 (Box Box 1)
- Indenture: Joseph Michaux to John Blanton, 1792 July 2 (Box Box 1)
- Note "Copies of letters", 1794 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Seymour Wright, 1794 June 28 (Box Box 1)
- Richard Randolph Jr. to Creed Taylor, 1795 January 28 (Box Box 1)
- Richard Randolph Jr. to Creed Taylor, 1795 April 25 (Box Box 1)
- Richard Randolph Jr. to Creed Taylor, 1795 June 6 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Bushrod Washington (copy), 1796 February 7
- Bond: William Randolph to Beverly Randolph, 1796 July 25 (Box Box 1)
- Jonas Chapham to Creed Taylor, 1796 October 1 (Box Box 1)
- Richard Randolph Jr. to Creed Taylor, 1796 (Box Box 1)
- Account: Thomas Gibson to Col. Beverly Randolph, 1796 (Box Box 1)
- Account: John Woodson to Creed Taylor, Exec. of Beverly Randolph, 1797 June 30 (Box Box 1)
- Account: Joseph Mettauer to Estate of Beverly Randolph, certified by Samuel W. Venable, 1797 July 17 (Box Box 1)
- Accounts of Creed Taylor as Executor of Beverly Randolph, ca. 1797 (Box Box 1)
- Judith Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1797 November 18 (Box Box 1)
- Judith Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1798 February 29 (Box Box 1)
- Receipt: William Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1798 May 3 (Box Box 1)
- Receipt: Woodson Daniel to Creed Taylor, 1798 May 4 (Box Box 1)
- John Randolph Jr. to Creed Taylor, 1798 September 16 (Box Box 1)
- Samuel Taylor Jr. to Creed Taylor, 1798 October 20 (Box Box 1)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1798 October 20 (Box Box 1)
- M. Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1798 December 12
- Judith Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1798 (Box Box 1)
- Clerk's bill, 1798 (Box Box 1)
- Account: William Randolph and James Trentwell, 1799 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Thomas Gibson, 1799 February 22 (Box Box 1)
- Meriwether Jones to Creed Taylor, 1799 April 9 (Box Box 1)
- John Taylor of Caroline to Creed Taylor, 1799 April 10 (Box Box 1)
- Bond: Martha Randolph & William Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1799 May 20 (Box Box 1)
- Receipt: John Wickham to Creed Taylor, 1799 June 10 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to James Wood, 1799 July 18 (Box Box 1)
- Judith Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1799 November 27 (Box Box 1)
- Sheriff's receipt to Creed Taylor, 1799 (Box Box 1)
- Thomas Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1799 (Box Box 1)
- William Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1799 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Thomas J. Davis, 1800
- Creed Taylor to John Wickham, 1800 July 16 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Rob Pleasant, 1800 July 26 (Box Box 1)
- John Wickham to Creed Taylor, 1800 September 8 (Box Box 1)
- Archibald Stuart to Creed Taylor, 1800 October 3 (Box Box 1)
- Judith Randolph to Mrs. Creed Taylor, 1800 October 24 (Box Box 1)
- Receipt: John Wickham to Creed Taylor, 1800 December 23 (Box Box 1)
- Judith Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1801 January 10 (Box Box 1)
- John Wickham to Creed Taylor, 1801 January 15 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to John Wickham, 1801 March 18 (Box Box 1)
- D.M. Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1801 May 29 (Box Box 1)
- John Randolph Jr. to Creed Taylor, 1801 July 25 (Box Box 1)
- John Randolph, Jr. to Creed Taylor, 1801 October 16 (Box Box 1)
- Receipt: Benjamin Hatcher to Creed Taylor, exec. of Beverly Randolph, 1801 (Box Box 1)
- John Randolph Jr. to Creed Taylor, 1802 January 31 (Box Box 1)
- James Monroe to Creed Taylor, 1802 February 1 (Box Box 1)
- Edmund Harrison to Creed Taylor, 1802 July 16 (Box Box 1)
- Archibald Stuart to Creed Taylor, 1802 November 27 (Box Box 1)
- Judith Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1803 January 1 (Box Box 1)
- Indenture: Thomas Taylor & Blake B. Woodson, Cumberland County, Virginia copy 1820, 1803 January 14 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Mrs. Smith, 1803 February 16 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor: Opinion on the Will of W.M. Macon, 1803 February 20 (Box Box 1)
- Abraham Sandefur to Creed Taylor, 1803 March 9 (Box Box 1)
- Daniel Call: Opinion on the Will of W.M. Macon, 1803 March 17 (Box Box 1)
- Eldred Simkins to Creed Taylor, 1803 May 17 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Eldred Simkins, 1803 July 1 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Richard Gibson, 1803 July 22 (Box Box 1)
- Eldred Simkins to Creed Taylor, 1803 August 1 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Moses Fisk, regarding the Virginia-Kentucky Boundary, 1803 August 10 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to the Sheriff of Prince Edward County, Virginia., 1803 August 25 (Box Box 1)
- John Taylor to [?], 1803 November 25 (Box Box 1)
- Account: Creed Taylor as executor of Beverly Randolph, 1803 (Box Box 1)
- John Randolph, Jr. To Creed Taylor, 1803 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Col. Thomas Read, 1804 April 3 (Box Box 1)
- Thomas Read to Creed Taylor, 1804 April 7 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Thomas Read, 1804 April 10 (Box Box 1)
- Eldred Simkins to Creed Taylor, 1804 August 10 (Box Box 1)
- Blake B. Woodson to Creed Taylor, 1804 August 11 (Box Box 1)
- Eldred Simkins to Creed Taylor, 1804 August 14 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Josiah Morton -- encl. by Josiah Morton, 1804 November 24 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor, a book endorsement, 1804 December 13 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Dr. Foushee, 1805 February 8 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Charles Clark, 1805 February 17 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to William Murray, 1805 February 22 (Box Box 1)
- Alex McRae to Creed Taylor, 1805 March 1 (Box Box 1)
- Eldred Simkins to Creed Taylor, 1805 March 8 (Box Box 1)
- Eldred Simkins to Creed Taylor, 1805 April 30 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to [?], 1805 July 11 (Box Box 1)
- Eldred Simkins to Creed Taylor, 1805 July 20 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to William Cowan, 1805 August 30 (Box Box 1)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1805 September 16 (Box Box 1)
- Alexander Stuart to Creed Taylor, 1805 November 3 (Box Box 1)
- Decision in case of Executors of John Lidderdale vs. Executors of Thomas M. Randolph, 1805 (Box Box 1)
- William Daniel to Creed Taylor, 1805 December 25 (Box Box 1)
- Typescripts of letters from: 1793 and 1805, Anne Cary Randolph; 1827 January 28, Maria B. Randolph; 1817 September 16, William Randolph, ca 1805-1807 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Thomas Watson, 1806 March 20 (Box Box 1)
- Statement of Account: Lidderdale vs. Randolph, 1805 November 27 (Box Box 1)
- From Creed Taylor to Joseph Wharton, 1806 March (Box Box 1)
- William P. Law to Creed Taylor, 1806 May 2 (Box Box 1)
- Archibald Stuart to Creed Taylor, 1806 August 29 (Box Box 1)
- Archibald Stuart to Creed Taylor, 1806 September 12 (Box Box 1)
- J.J. Monroe to Creed Taylor, 1806 September 19 (Box Box 1)
- J.B. Robertson to Creed Taylor, 1806 October 15 (Box Box 1)
- William H. Cabell: Commission to Creed Taylor as Judge in chancery court, 1806 December 4 (Box Box 1)
- Judith Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1807 February 3 (Box Box 1)
- Judith Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1807 May 3 (Box Box 1)
- Henry E. Watkins to Creed Taylor, 1807 August 20 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to [?]; on James Monroe and the Presidency, 1807 December 21 (Box Box 1)
- Letters of Judith Randolph, 1807 (Box Box 1)
  Typed transcript of three letters by Judith Randolph.
- Creed Taylor to some gentlemen of the bar, 1808 January 22 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to William B. Giles, 1808 March 22 (Box Box 1)
- William B. Giles to Creed Taylor, 1808 March 27 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to William B. Giles, 1808 April 2 (Box Box 1)
- Samuel Tyler to Creed Taylor, 1808 April 3 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to R. N. V. [Venable?], 1808 April 18 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Mrs. Fanny Crump, 1808 November 16 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to [?], ca. 1808 (Box Box 1)
- James Monroe to Creed Taylor, ca. 1808 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to [?], ca. 1808 (Box Box 1)
- Debt of Lidderdale vs. Randolph: William Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1809 January 9 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Thomas Mann Randolph, 1809 January 19 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Mr. Hay, note on verso, 1812 August, 1809 January 28 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to R.B., 1809 January 29 (Box Box 1)
- William Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1809 April 1
- Creed Taylor to Judge Cobourn, 1809 April 12 (Box Box 1)
- Alexander Stuart to Creed Taylor, 1809 July 14 (Box Box 1)
- Thomas Mann Randolph to William Randolph. End by Creed Taylor, 1809 September 8 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to D. Carr, 1809 November. 21 (Box Box 1)
- John Minor to Creed Taylor, 1809 November 30 (Box Box 1)
- Archibald Stuart to Creed Taylor, 1809 December 20 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to [?], 1809 December 21 (Box Box 1)
- Letters of Martha [Randolph] and Lucy B. Randolph, 1810 (Box Box 1)
- Judith Randolph, 1810 (Box Box 1)
  4 pp.; incomplete.
- Sa[muel] Myres and others to Creed Taylor, 1810 February 20 (Box Box 1)
- Martha Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1810 February 20 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Mr. Mason, et al., 1810 February 22 (Box Box 1)
- M. Randolph to Mrs. Creed Taylor, 1810 June 24 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to Ed C. Stanard, 1810 July 6 (Box Box 1)
- William Wirt to Creed Taylor, 1810 July 22 (Box Box 1)
- Creed Taylor to William G. Pendleton, 1811 January 16
- James Monroe to Creed Taylor, 1811 January 21 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Spencer Roane, 1811 June 9 (Box Box 2)
- Spencer Roane to Creed Taylor, 1811 June 9 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Benjamin Botts, 1811 November 24 (Box Box 2)
- Archibald Stuart to Creed Taylor, 1812 January 19 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Charles K. Mallory, Pres. of the Council of States, 1812 May 5 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Mr. Hay on Politics; See Verso of item 1809 January 27, 1812 August (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Alexander McRae, 1812 September 8 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Christopher B. Strong, 1812 December 26 (Box Box 2)
- James Madison to [?], 1813 January 4 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to James Monroe, 1813 May 24 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Gov. James Barbour, 1813 July 11 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Gen. Robert Taylor, 1813 September 18 (Box Box 2)
- Dabney Carr to Creed Taylor, 1813 September 19 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Wal. Holcombe, 1813 December 27 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Judy Anderson and Mrs. Holcombe, 1813 December 27 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Gen. John Minor, 1814 March 15 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Robert Nelson, 1814 July 18 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to John Brown, 1814 September 30 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Philip Norborne Nicholas, 1814 October 22 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Archibald Thweatte, 1814 October 22 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Thomas Read, Jr., 1814 October 29 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to John Michaux, 1815 February 3 (Box Box 2)
- Nat Dodson, Statement of a Conversation, etc, 1815 July 21 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to [?], 1815 July 31 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Nath. Harris, 1815 August 9 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Blake B. Woodson, 1815 September 17 (Box Box 2)
- Virginia Circuit Court: Dismissal of Case Against William W. Hening, 1815 November 14 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to H. Clarke, 1816 March 28 (Box Box 2)
- John Blanton: Obligation for Land, 1816 October 21 (Box Box 2)
- Agnes Vauter to John C. Allen, 1816 October 28 (Box Box 2)
- Richmond Chancery Court: Orders Regarding Bond of Clerk, 1817 January (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor, Jr. to Creed Taylor, 1817 February 1 (Box Box 2)
- Bond, as Clerk of Superior Court of Chancery, Richmond, Virginia: William W. Hening, 1817 February 6 (Box Box 2)
- J. H. Chew to Creed Taylor, 1817 May 7 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1817 July 23 (Box Box 2)
- Dabney Carr to Creed Taylor, 1817 July 29 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1817Aug 4 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1817 August 26 (Box Box 2)
- William Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1817 September 16 (Box Box 2)
- Dabney Carr to Creed Taylor, 1817 September 30 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1817 December 21 (Box Box 2)
- Spencer Roane to Creed Taylor, 1817 (Box Box 2)
- Daniel Call to Creed Taylor. Endorsement by Benjamin Watkins Leigh, 1818 February 7 (Box Box 2)
- Certificate: William Munford, 1818 February 24 (Box Box 2)
- William Munford to Creed Taylor, 1818 March 13 (Box Box 2)
- Mrs. Polly R. Cowardin to Creed Taylor, 1818 March 31 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to William W. Hening, 1819 September 6 (Box Box 2)
- Opinion: Grahm vs. Hatcher, 1820 March 9 (Box Box 2)
- Chancery Court Order, Owen vs. Mayes, 1820 November 29 (Box Box 2)
- Chancery Court: Dismissal of Case of Samuel Booker, 1821 January 15 (Box Box 2)
- Robert P. Headley to Creed Taylor, 1821 July 2 (Box Box 2)
- Affidavit: Robert P. Headley, 1821 July 22 (Box Box 2)
- S.W. Venable: Statement in the Case of Robert P. Headley and John B. Braham, 1821 July 24 (Box Box 2)
- John S. Nash: Statement Regarding Robert P. Headley and John B. Braham, 1821 July 24
- Benjamin Watkins Leigh to Creed Taylor, 1821 August 12 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Benjamin W. Leigh, 1821 August 17 (Box Box 2)
- James T. Morehead to Creed Taylor, 1821 December 23 (Box Box 2)
- Bond to President and Directors of the Literary Fund: Creed Taylor and Samuel Taylor, 1822 April 16 (Box Box 2)
- James Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1822 November 12 (Box Box 2)
- William Fleming to Creed Taylor, 1822 November 20 (Box Box 2)
- James T. Morehead to Creed Taylor, 1823 January 2 (Box Box 2)
- Francis Taliaferro Brooke to Creed Taylor, 1823 February 19 (Box Box 2)
- John W. Green to Creed Taylor, 1823 February 20 (Box Box 2)
- William H. Cabell to Creed Taylor, 1823 February 21 (Box Box 2)
- Daniel Call to Creed Taylor, 1823 February 24 (Box Box 2)
- John Robertson to Creed Taylor, 1823 February 26 (Box Box 2)
- Robert Stanard to Creed Taylor, 1823 March 4 (Box Box 2)
- Thomas Jefferson to Creed Taylor, 1823 March 24 (Box Box 2)
- C. Johnson to Creed Taylor, 1823 May 12 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1823 August 28 (Box Box 2)
- Anne Cary Randolph Morris and Martha Randolph Letters, Fragments of Typescripts, 1824 August 23 (Box Box 2)
- Martha Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1824 August 28 (Box Box 2)
- Warrant Against John Wheeler: Creed Taylor, 1824 September 20 (Box Box 2)
- Certificate to John Wheeler: Creed Taylor, 1824 September 21 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1824 October 31 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1824 October 31 (Box Box 2)
- Francis Brooke to Creed Taylor, 1824 November 30 (Box Box 2)
- James T. Morehead to Creed Taylor, 1825 October 2 (Box Box 2)
- Thomas Mann Randolph to Creed Taylor, 1825 October 29 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to James T. Morehead, ca. October 1825 (Box Box 2)
- John S. Fleming to Creed Taylor, 1826 January 18 (Box Box 2)
- [?] to Creed Taylor, 1826 January 19 (Box Box 2)
- John S. Fleming to Creed Taylor, 1826 January 20 (Box Box 2)
- Order as Chancellor in Vacation: Creed Taylor, 1826 June 30 (Box Box 2)
- Opinion on Hening's Case in Vacation: Creed Taylor, 1826 August 7 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1826 August 28 (Box Box 2)
- James Innes to Creed Taylor, 1826 August 28 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor, fragment, 1826 December 30 (Box Box 2)
- Maria B. Randolph to Mrs. Creed Taylor, 1827 January 28 (Box Box 2)
- [?] to Creed Taylor, 1827 February 19 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1827 November 22 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1827 December 2 (Box Box 2)
- Court Orders in the case of Peterfield Edwards Estate: Creed Taylor, 1827 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Pulliam to Creed Taylor, endorsing Hening's Bond, 1828 January 11 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to John S. Fleming, fragment, 1828 January 19 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1828 February 7 (Box Box 2)
- James Garnett to Creed Taylor, 1828 February 28 (Box Box 2)
- Benjamin Watkins Leigh to Creed Taylor, 1828 April 2 (Box Box 2)
- Account: Creed Taylor to M. Le Grand, 1828 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1828 (Box Box 2)
- Document Concerning the Virginia Chancery Courts, [ca.1828] (Box Box 2)
- H. Rhodes to Creed Taylor, 1829 August 29 (Box Box 2)
- Account: William D. Jones to Creed Taylor, 1829 October 1 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1829 October 18 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1830 March 7 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor, Jr. to Creed Taylor, 1830 March 14 (Box Box 2)
- William H. Cabell, D. Carr and Creed Taylor -- License to Creed Taylor, Jr. to Practice Law, 1831 January 31 (Box Box 2)
- William G. Pendleton to Creed Taylor, 1831 April 14 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1832 March 5 (Box Box 2)
- Ed. W. Sims to Creed Taylor, 1832 July 31 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1832 September 18 (Box Box 2)
- J. Guerrant to Creed Taylor, 1832 December 9 (Box Box 2)
- Plot and Survey of Flat Lick, Cumberland County, Va.: Edward Redford, 1833 February (Box Box 2)
- John Chrisp to Creed Taylor, 1833 March 27 (Box Box 2)
- Receipt: William D. Jones to Creed Taylor, 1833 March 26 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to William D. Jones, 1833 April 16 (Box Box 2)
- Creed Taylor to Samuel Taylor, 1833 April 17 (Box Box 2)
- Indenture: Creed Taylor and the Bank of the United States, 1833 May 15 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1834 January 21 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, 1834 (Box Box 2)
- W. G. Gholson to Mrs. Creed Taylor, 1836 February 19 (Box Box 2)
- Blank Contract, 1838 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Mrs. Creed Taylor, 1839 April 29 (Box Box 2)
- Thomas Worthington to Creed Taylor Jr., 1842 February 2 (Box Box 2)
- Promissory Note: G.R. Jeffers to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1844 August 19 (Box Box 2)
- Account: Robert Henderson to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1849 October 24 (Box Box 2)
- Jeannette Knickerbocker to Edwin Knickerbocker, 1850 April 24 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1851 April 13 (Box Box 2)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1851 December 2 (Box Box 2)
- Accounts and Receipts: Creed Taylor, Jr., 1850-1863 (Box Box 2)
- Diary [Jennette Knickerbocker], 1852 (Box Box 3)
- William F. Taylor to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1853 February 23 (Box Box 3)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1853 April 17 (Box Box 3)
- R. F. Lester to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1853 October 27 (Box Box 3)
- School Teacher's Diary [Jennette Knickerbocker], 1853-56 (Box Box 3)
- S.C. Gholson to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1854 November 23 (Box Box 3)
- Jennnette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1855 April 4 (Box Box 3)
- Samuel Taylor to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1855 June 2 (Box Box 3)
- S.C. Gholson to [?], 1855 August 1 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1856 February 27 (Box Box 3)
- Annie J. Glasgow to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1856 October 13 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1857 January 1 (Box Box 3)
- Albert Howard, Jr. to Jennette Knickerbocker, 1857 January 12 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1857 January 19 (Box Box 3)
- Albert Howard, Jr. to Jennette Knickerbocker, 1857 January 28 (Box Box 3)
- M.J.N. Glasgow to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1857 January (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1857 February 21 (Box Box 3)
- Albert Howard to Jennette Knickerbocker, 1857 April 20 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1857 April 26 (Box Box 3)
- Albert Howard Jr. to Jennette Knickerbocker, 1857 June 25 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard Jr., 1857 July 12 (Box Box 3)
- Receipt: W. A. Wilson to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1857 August 15 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr, 1857 August 17 (Box Box 3)
- Albert Howard to Jennette Knickerbocker, 1857 August 23 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1857 September 1 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1857 Sept 27 (Box Box 3)
- Albert Howard, Jr. To Jennette Knickerbocker, 1857 October 9 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1857 October 9 (Box Box 3)
- Albert Howard, Jr. To Jennette Knickerbocker, 1857 October 17 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1857 October 28 (Box Box 3)
- Albert Howard, Jr. to Jennette Knickerbocker, 1857 November 22 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1857 December 1 (Box Box 3)
- Albert Howard, Jr. to Jennette Knickerbocker, 1857 December 27 (Box Box 3)
- Receipt: Morton Riddle to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1857 December 31 (Box Box 3)
- Account: C.H. Barksdale to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1857 (Box Box 3)
- Jennette Knickerbocker to Albert Howard, Jr., 1858 January 3 (Box Box 3)
- Albert Howard, Jr. To Jennette Knickerbocker, 1858 January 8 (Box Box 3)
- Memorandum of money paid: Creed Taylor, Jr., 1858 June 19 (Box Box 3)
- Receipts, Tuition accounts: B. Gould to Creed Taylor, 1858 June 26 (Box Box 3)
- N.C. Griswold to [?], 1858 December 8 (Box Box 3)
- Accounts and Receipts: William M. Carroll to Creed Taylor, Jr., 1858 (Box Box 3)